Okay, so now that the installation process is done, let's build our IoT platform.
But first of all, what are our requirements?
What we want to do is to have a simple dashboard with two datas: the temperature, which is the user
payload sent by the device and the RSSI
so we can track the signal power received on the gateway for a specific device.
We're going to do this in three steps.
First, we're going to build an MQTT subscriber on Node-RED to get the uplink data.
We've done it already in the previous chapter, but we'll do it quickly again.
And at any time, if we want to check if the Node-RED configuration is correct, we'll use a debug node
to display the logs and verify that everything works well.
Secondly, among all the data received on the subscriber node, we're going to extract the exact value
we want to use for our dashboard.
In our case it will be the temperature and the RSSI.
And finally we'll send the temperature on the RSSI value to the Influxdb database. To check that the values
have been stored properly,
we'll connect the database thanks to the Influxdb user interface and check that our data are available.
The third and last step is to tell Grafana how it can access the database.
So we'll configure it with all the required value and credentials.
Then we'll just have to create a new request with the name and the range of time of the needed value.
Again, our value will be the temperature and the RSSI.
Let's start with the first step in the next video.